Kalynn Kosyka

kkosyka.github.io | kkosyka@smith.edu | github.com/kkosyka

Objective

An experience that will allow me to use my problem solving skills, quick learner, my attention to detail, and gain exposure to new
methodologies to further develop my abilities in the field of Computer Science and/or Data Sciences. In addition, collaborating with an
inspiring, brilliant, and productive team that share common goals to push boundaries and change the world.

Education

SMITH COLLEGE

- · 1 Chapin Way, Northampton, MA 01063
- · Junior, Expected Graduation: May 2019
- · Majors: Computer Science & Statistical Data Sciences
- · Current GPA: 3.83 (September 2017), Dean's List 2016-2017
- · Clubs: Smithies in CS, Smith College Ceramics Club, Smith College Cycling Club, and University of Massachusetts Amherst Cycling
- · Related coursework: Introduction to Computer Science Through Programming (Python), Interactive Web Documents (HTML, CSS, JavaScript), Program with Data Structures (Java), Theory of Computation (Python), Communicating with Data, Computer Graphics (HTML, JavaScript), Microprocessor & Assembly Language (Assembly Language), Linear Algebra, Introduction to Data Sciences (R)
- · Current related coursework: Introduction to Probability and Statistics, Introduction to Operating Systems, Database Systems

Skills

CODING

· Python, Java, JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SQL, R, Assembly Language

Experience

GEOPROGRAMMER/OCIP: SPATIAL ANALYSIS LAB | SMITH COLLEGE | SPRING 2016 - CURRENT

- · Work-study at Smith College, Northampton, MA
- · Assist Jon Caris, director of Spatial Analysis Lab at Smith College, with specific projects that require writing code.
- $\cdot \ \ \text{Self taught, creating applications that solve day to day problems or visualize geographic phenomenon to help share with public.}$

CYBERHEALTHGIS | TEXAS A&M UNIVERSITY | SUMMER 2017

- $\cdot \ \ Research\ Experience\ for\ Undergraduates\ (REU)\ supported\ by\ the\ US\ National\ Science\ Foundation\ (NSF\ Project\#\ 1560106).$
- · A 10-week research program for undergraduate students interested in technology, geography, and health.
- · Self taught data wrangling through Python using Pandas, Seaborn, NumPy.
- · Collaborated with faculty and graduate students in computer science defining, conducting, and presenting research projects. Researched how to detect road surface through cycling using wearable devices and machine learning tree algorithms.

DOG WALKER | WAG! WALKING | SUMMER 2016 - SUMMER 2017

- · New York, NY
- · Certified and experienced pet care provider. Passionately care for the wellbeing of dogs.

MENTORSHIP | NEW YORK STATE PSYCHIATRY INSTITUTE - COLUMBIA UNIVERSITY | SUMMER 2016

- · New York, NY
- · Mentorship with Spiro Pantazatos, guided through coding to learn and be exposed to programs that involved neuroimaging and analysis. Using Python and Nipype to manipulate MRIs and analysis fMRIs using FSL and SPM.

DINING HALL STAFF | SMITH COLLEGE | FALL 2015 - SPRING 2016

- · Work-study at Smith College, Northampton, MA
- $\cdot\,$ Tasks that include maintaining clean dishes, tables, and floors.

STUDENT | GIRLS WHO CODE | FALL 2014 - SPRING 2015

- · Spotify, New York, NY
- · A national nonprofit organization that is working to close the gender gap in the technology and engineering sectors. With support from public and private partners, Girls Who Code works to educate, inspire, and equip high school girls with the skills and resources to pursue opportunities in computing fields.

Projects

DRONEGALLERY

- · Spring 2017, Spatial Analysis Lab (JavaScript, HTML, CSS)
- · A tool to display drone flights done by Spatial Analysis Lab of Smith College under Jon Caris. Created an interface for users to view drone images on an interactive map and displays data (name, date, coordinates, and description) via GeoServer (.TIF) and local JSON.
- · https://github.com/kkosyka/DroneGallery

PARTICIPATORY SENSING OF CYCLING PATH SAFETY WITH WEARABLE DEVICES AND MACHINE LEARNING

- · Summer 2017, CyberHealthGIS REU (Python)
- · Research to detect road surface quality (brick road, grass, irregular bumps, and smooth pavement) through cycling using accelerometers in wearable devices and machine learning.
- · Presented in two poster sessions
- · https://github.com/kkosyka/CyberHealthGIS/blob/master/KosykaPoster.pdf

Hackathons

HACK@SMITH - SPRING 2017 (awarded best domain name - http://www.costumecat.tech)

HACK@SMITH - SPRING 2016

HACKHOLYOKE - FALL 2016